Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
Today, we're bringing you an upper intermediate lesson and something that we all do.
今天，我们带来了一节中高级课程，内容是我们都会做的事情。
Right, talking to ourselves.
没错，自言自语。
Talking to ourselves, right?
自言自语，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
I think everyone does it.
我觉得每个人都做过。
You think to yourself or you talk to yourself.
你会在心里想，或者直接说出来。
Yeah.
嗯。
And we're going to be doing that today, but we're going to be looking at some specific
我们今天就要做这件事，但我们会关注一些特定的
vocabulary.
词汇。
Erika, why don't you tell us about that?
Erika，你来给我们讲讲吧？
Well, unfortunately, we're going to be following a guy as he's in a really embarrassing situation
嗯，不幸的是，我们要跟一个家伙，他正处在一个非常尴尬的处境，
and we're going to hear him call himself some bad names in his mind.
我们会听到他在心里骂自己。
So he's a little bit nervous and he thinks he is not very smart, right?
所以他有点紧张，觉得自己不太聪明，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so before we start with this dialogue, there are a couple of words that we should
好的，在我们开始这段对话之前，有几个词我们需要
look at in vocabulary preview.
在词汇预览中看一下。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
All right, we're going to hear both of these words in the dialogue.
好的，这两个词我们都会在对话里听到。
And the first one is famished.
第一个是famished。
Famished.
Famished。
Okay, so famished is an adjective.
好的，famished是一个形容词。
That's right, meaning very, very, very hungry.
没错，意思是特别特别饿。
Very, very hungry.
非常非常饿。
Okay, so just very hungry, very easy.
好的，就是很饿，很简单。
Yes.
是的。
Famished.
Famished。
Now, what about our next one?
那下一个呢？
Sexist.
Sexist。
Another adjective to describe a person, right?
另一个形容词，用来形容人，对吧？
Right.
对。
Or a thing, I guess.
或者事物，我想。
Like, yeah, an idea.
比如，嗯，一种想法。
Okay, so a sexist person would be?
好的，那一个性别歧视的人会怎样？
Somebody who judges people by their sex.
就是根据性别来判断别人的人。
Okay.
好的。
So like all women are stupid, for example.
比如认为所有女人都很蠢。
Which is not true, of course.
这当然不是真的。
No, of course not.
不，当然不是。
Right?
对吧？
So sexist works both ways.
所以性别歧视是双向的。
Yes.
是的。
A woman can be sexist, a man could be sexist.
女人可以性别歧视，男人也可以。
Exactly.
没错。
Meaning the women thinks all men are stupid.
意思是女人认为所有男人都很蠢。
Which is also not true.
这也不是真的。
Yes.
是的。
Let's just be clear about that.
我们得说清楚这一点。
All right.
好的。
So now that we've taken a look at these two phrases, let's start with our dialogue and
现在我们看完了这两个短语，让我们开始对话，
we'll be back to talk about all the great words.
之后我们会回来讨论所有精彩的词汇。
Miss, your salad.
小姐，您的沙拉。
Mmm.
嗯。
Looks good.
看起来不错。
I'm positively famished.
我真是饿坏了。
And for you, sir.
这是您的，先生。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Enjoy.
请慢用。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I can't believe she's on a date with me.
真不敢相信她跟我约会。
I'm so lucky.
我太幸运了。
I must be the luckiest guy in the world.
我一定是世界上最幸运的家伙。
I want to scream at the top of my lungs.
我想大声尖叫。
I'm the luckiest dude in the world.
我是世界上最幸运的家伙。
Oh, shut up.
哦，闭嘴。
Don't be such a dumbass.
别这么白痴。
She's so hot.
她太性感了。
Wait, I can't say that.
等等，我不能这么说。
That's sexist.
那是性别歧视。
She's so hot.
她太性感了。
She's making me sexist.
她让我变得性别歧视。
Oh my God.
哦，天哪。
I'm such a tool.
我真是个废物。
Okay, get it together.
好了，振作起来。
She's eating salad.
她在吃沙拉。
All right.
好的。
I have a salad.
我也有沙拉。
Oh, crap.
哦，糟了。
Which fork do I use?
我该用哪把叉子？
Damn it.
该死。
She's going to think I'm a moron.
她会觉得我是个傻瓜。
What the hell are all these forks for?
这些叉子都是干嘛用的？
Which one did she use?
她用了哪一把？
Okay, chill.
好了，冷静。
I'm going to use this one.
我要用这把。
Which one did she use?
她用了哪一把？
Okay, chill.
好了，冷静。
Be cool.
冷静点。
Just take a fork.
就拿一把叉子。
Okay, embarrassing first date, huh?
好吧，尴尬的第一次约会，是吧？
Yeah, I mean I really do feel sorry for this guy.
是啊，我真的很同情这家伙。
Well, it happens to us.
嗯，我们都会遇到这种事。
Sometimes we are in the company of a very beautiful girl and we just get really nervous.
有时候跟一个很漂亮的女孩在一起，我们就会变得非常紧张。
Alright, well, you know, psychologists call this negative self-talk.
好吧，你知道，心理学家把这叫做消极自我对话。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah, this sort of calling yourself names and talking negatively about yourself.
是的，就是这种骂自己、说消极话的行为。
But actually you can use some of this language to talk negatively about others.
但实际上你也可以用这些语言来消极地评价别人。
Yeah.
是的。
So why don't we look now at this language in Language Takeaway.
那我们来看看语言要点里的这些表达吧。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So on Language Takeaway today we have five words.
今天的语言要点我们有五个词。
Let's start with our first one.
从第一个开始。
Dumbass.
Dumbass。
Okay, now this isn't a very polite word I would say.
好的，我得说这不是一个很礼貌的词。
Definitely not polite.
绝对不礼貌。
Okay, but what is a dumbass?
好的，那dumbass是什么意思？
Well, it's obviously a dumb, stupid idiot.
嗯，显然是指一个愚蠢、笨拙的白痴。
Okay, so it's a person that is not very intelligent.
好的，就是不太聪明的人。
And our next word is also quite similar.
下一个词也很类似。
Moron.
Moron。
A moron.
一个moron。
If a person is a dumbass or a person is a moron, what's the difference?
如果一个人是dumbass或moron，有什么区别？
Well, basically a moron is someone who is not smart, who is very unintelligent.
嗯，基本上moron是指不聪明、非常笨的人。
Okay.
好的。
So they don't know what one plus one is.
所以他们连一加一都不知道。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
明白了。
But a dumbass is a person who does stupid things.
但dumbass是指做蠢事的人。
Okay.
好的。
So maybe a dumbass like you're planning a bank robbery and the dumbass forgets to bring
比如你计划抢银行，但那个dumbass忘了带
the gun.
枪。
Okay.
好的。
That is a dumbass.
那就是dumbass。
All right.
明白了。
So maybe moron is a little bit less offensive and it's actually you'll find it in the dictionary,
所以moron可能稍微不那么冒犯，而且你会在字典里找到它，
right?
对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Whereas a dumbass I don't think you'll find it.
而dumbass我觉得字典里找不到。
Yeah, it's slang.
是的，是俚语。
It's slang.
是俚语。
Exactly.
没错。
Now what about this next?
那下一个呢？
It's also a negative name you can call people.
这也是一个可以用来骂人的负面称呼。
A tool.
A tool。
Tool.
Tool。
This is very strange because I don't know how a tool can be something negative towards
这很奇怪，因为我不知道tool怎么能用来负面地形容
a person.
一个人。
Yeah.
是啊。
But it actually means the opposite, right?
但实际上它的意思相反，对吧？
If a person is called a tool, it means they are useless, right?
如果一个人被叫做tool，意思是他们没用，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
So if you ever call the tool, they're saying that you're useless.
所以如果你被人叫tool，就是说你没用。
Exactly.
没错。
You're good for nothing.
你一无是处。
All right.
好的。
Well, these are three interesting words.
嗯，这三个词挺有意思的。
So why don't we hear some examples of each of these words in use?
那我们听一些每个词的使用例子吧？
Example one.
例子一。
I hate Tom.
我讨厌Tom。
He's such a dumbass.
他真是个白痴。
Last week he borrowed my mobile phone and dropped it in the pool.
上周他借了我的手机，掉进了游泳池。
Example two.
例子二。
I don't like Kevin very much.
我不太喜欢Kevin。
He can be a real moron at times.
他有时候真是个傻瓜。
Example three.
例子三。
It was looking for a joke, but he didn't even have a resume prepared.
他在找工作，但连简历都没准备。
He's such a tool.
他真是个废物。
Okay, so great examples and here at EnglishPod, we're bringing you real street talk.
好的，很好的例子，在EnglishPod，我们给你带来真实的街头用语。
Exactly.
没错。
Language as it is spoken by today's youth.
就像当今年轻人说的那样。
Okay.
好的。
Now let's take a look at our last two words.
现在我们来看最后两个词。
All right.
好的。
Well, these phrases you can use when you're trying to calm yourself down and make yourself
嗯，这些短语可以用来让自己冷静下来，
relax a little bit, right?
放松一点，对吧？
Right.
对。
Let's take a look at the next one.
我们来看下一个。
Chill.
Chill。
Okay.
好的。
Chill.
Chill。
So again, relax.
所以又是放松。
Calm down.
冷静。
Relax.
放松。
Chill.
Chill。
Yes.
是的。
And then you also need to be cool.
然后你还需要be cool。
Be cool.
Be cool。
冷静点。
Now if you can tell the pattern is related to temperature, right?
现在如果你能看出这个模式跟温度有关，对吧？
Chill is cold.
Chill 是冷的意思。
Cool is similar to cold.
Cool 和 cold 类似。
So again, that's what it means to relax.
所以，这就是放松的意思。
To calm down your emotions.
让你的情绪平静下来。
Make your emotions not so hot.
让你的情绪不那么“热”。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So chill.
所以 chill。
Be cool.
冷静点。
Exactly.
没错。
And you use them together like that, don't you?
你经常把它们一起用，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Now chill also has another way of using it, right?
现在 chill 还有另一种用法，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
I'm chilling with my friends.
我和朋友们在 chill。
Yeah.
是的。
We're chilling here in the EnglishPod studio.
我们在 EnglishPod 录音室里 chill。
Which means we're just relaxing.
意思就是我们只是在放松。
We are just having fun.
我们只是在玩。
Not doing anything, right?
什么都不做，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
But you can't say chilling.
但你不能说 chilling。
You have to drop the G. Yeah.
你得把 G 省掉。是的。
You have to drop.
你得省掉。
Right.
对。
You can't say I'm chilling.
你不能说 I'm chilling。
You have to say I'm chilling.
你得说 I'm chilling。
I'm chilling.
I'm chilling。
Okay.
好的。
So that's all for language takeaway.
这就是语言要点的全部内容。
But now let's take a look at some of the really useful phrases that we saw in this dialogue
但现在让我们看看在流利度提升部分
in Fluency Builder.
这个对话里的一些非常有用的短语。
Okay.
好的。
So this guy is so happy he's on this date that he wants to scream at the top of his
所以这家伙在约会中太开心了，他想
lungs.
放声尖叫。
Scream at the top of my lungs.
So basically he just wants to scream.
所以他基本上就是想尖叫。
To shout really loudly.
大声喊叫。
Really loudly.
非常大声。
Yeah.
是的。
He's so excited, right?
他太兴奋了，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So for example, sometimes you're at a concert, right?
比如，有时候你在演唱会，对吧？
Yep.
嗯。
And you need to talk to your friend and you're screaming at the top of your lungs because
你需要跟朋友说话，于是你声嘶力竭地大喊，因为
the other person can't hear you.
对方听不见你说话。
Exactly.
没错。
So you're lost in the woods and you need to scream at the top of your lungs so that someone
所以你在森林里迷路了，需要声嘶力竭地大喊，这样别人
will hear you and find you.
才能听到你并找到你。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
Okay.
好的。
So scream at the top of my lungs.
所以“声嘶力竭地大喊”。
Our next phrase.
我们的下一个短语。
Get it together.
振作起来。
So if I tell you, Erica, you need to get it together.
所以如果我告诉你，Erica，你需要振作起来。
Basically you're telling me to calm down, relax.
基本上是在告诉你要冷静、放松。
So pull your emotions together, get your ideas straight.
就是整理好情绪，理清思路。
Right.
对。
So it kind of gives you this idea that you got to pull, like you said, pull your emotions
所以它给人一种感觉，就是你必须把，就像你说的，把情绪
together in a little box and tie them up.
收进一个小盒子里，绑起来。
All right.
好的。
So get it together.
所以“振作起来”。
Yep.
嗯。
So Marco, when would you use this phrase, get it together?
那么Marco，你什么时候会用这个短语“振作起来”？
I guess when somebody is either very emotional, maybe crying or very nervous, you tell the
我想是当某人情绪非常激动，比如在哭或者很紧张的时候，你会对
person, oh, get it together, relax.
那个人说，哦，振作起来，放松。
Or when somebody maybe is not doing something good in their life, like making bad decisions
或者当某人在生活中做得不好，比如做出糟糕的决定
or not being responsible, you tell that person, you need to get it together.
或者不负责任时，你会告诉那个人，你需要振作起来。
Exactly.
没错。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
I couldn't have said it better myself.
我自己都说不这么好了。
Okay.
好的。
So now why don't we move on to our next phrase?
那么现在我们为什么不继续下一个短语呢？
And this is really, really high frequency.
这个短语的使用频率真的非常高。
I think you would hear it all the time.
我想你会经常听到它。
All right.
好的。
So what the hell?
那么“what the hell”是什么意思？
What the hell?
“What the hell”？
So why would you say what the hell?
那你为什么会说“what the hell”？
Well, obviously you're asking a question, right?
嗯，显然你是在问一个问题，对吧？
Because you got your W, you got your what.
因为你有“W”，你有“what”。
But when you say the hell, you're putting emphasis on the what.
但当你加上“the hell”时，你是在强调“what”。
So you're asking a really strong question.
所以你是在问一个非常强烈的问题。
Right.
对。
It's not polite.
这不礼貌。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So if I say what the hell is going on?
所以如果我说“what the hell is going on？”
What's happening?
发生了什么？
Really, really what's happening?
到底发生了什么？
Right?
对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
So, and we can change it a little bit.
那么，我们可以稍微改变一下。
We can replace the what with another WH like why, how, where, where or when.
我们可以把“what”换成其他WH词，比如“why”、“how”、“where”或“when”。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So why don't we hear some examples of how this expression is used using different WH
那我们为什么不听一些例子，看看这个表达如何用不同的WH
words?
词来使用？
Example one, where the hell are you?
例子一：你到底在哪里？
I've been waiting for hours.
我已经等了好几个小时了。
Example two, how the hell did you do that?
例子二：你到底是怎么做到的？
That was amazing.
那太棒了。
Example three, when the hell are you going to find a job?
例子三：你到底什么时候才能找到工作？
I'm tired of paying for everything.
我厌倦了为你付一切费用。
Example four, who the hell are you?
例子四：你到底是谁？
I don't know you.
我不认识你。
All right.
好的。
Now our final word, also a little bit strong, but pretty high frequency.
现在我们的最后一个词，也有点强烈，但使用频率很高。
Oh yeah.
哦，是的。
Very high frequency.
使用频率非常高。
Oh crap.
哦，糟了。
So it's a little bit strong, but less strong than maybe saying a really bad word.
所以这个词有点重，但比说一个真正的脏话要轻一些。
Right?
对吧？
Yes.
是的。
But it's definitely saying like you made a mistake.
但它绝对是在说你犯了个错误。
Right?
对吧？
Yeah.
嗯。
It's like a really strong, oh no.
它就像一个很强烈的“哦不”。
Oh no.
哦不。
Exactly.
没错。
A really strong, oh no.
一个很强烈的“哦不”。
Yeah.
嗯。
But I guess not many people say, oh no.
但我觉得没多少人会说“哦不”。
Oh no.
哦不。
I just lost $10 million.
我刚损失了一千万美元。
Exactly.
没错。
Right?
对吧？
You would not say that.
你不会那么说的。
Yeah.
嗯。
So it's a very strong, oh no, but it's not as strong as it could be.
所以它是一个很强烈的“哦不”，但还没到最强烈的程度。
There are other words out there that are stronger, but we are not going to go into them here.
还有更强烈的词，但我们这里就不深入讨论了。
But maybe you guys know, so let us know.
不过也许你们知道，那就告诉我们吧。
Yes.
是的。
We can definitely keep an eye out on the comment section.
我们肯定会留意评论区。
But don't write the words in the comment section.
但别在评论区写那些词。
Okay.
好的。
So we saw some really great phrases, some really great words, a lot of informal language,
所以我们看到了一些很棒的短语，一些很棒的词汇，很多非正式语言，
but it's very high frequency and you'll use that with your friends or you'll see it in
但这些都是高频词，你会和朋友用，或者在
movies, TV shows.
电影、电视剧里看到。
Yeah.
嗯。
Really common in movies and TV shows.
在电影和电视剧里非常常见。
Exactly.
没错。
So let's listen to this dialogue one more time and then we'll come back and talk a little
那我们再听一遍这段对话，然后回来再聊
bit more.
一点。
Miss, your salad.
小姐，您的沙拉。
Hmm.
嗯。
Looks good.
看起来不错。
I'm positively famished.
我真是饿坏了。
And for you, sir.
这是给您的，先生。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Enjoy.
请慢用。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I can't believe she's on a date with me.
真不敢相信她居然在跟我约会。
I'm so lucky.
我太幸运了。
I must be the luckiest guy in the world.
我一定是世界上最幸运的家伙。
Screaming at the top of my lungs, I'm the luckiest dude in the world!
我要放声大喊：我是世界上最幸运的家伙！
Oh, shut up!
哦，闭嘴吧！
Don't be such a dumbass.
别这么傻乎乎的。
She's so hot!
她太性感了！
Wait, I can't say that.
等等，我不能这么说。
I'm getting sexist.
我变得性别歧视了。
She's making me sexist. Oh my god!
她让我变得性别歧视了。天哪！
I'm such a tool!
我真是个傻瓜！
Okay, get it together.
好了，冷静下来。
She's eating salad. Oh right.
她在吃沙拉。哦，对了。
I have a salad.
我也有沙拉。
Oh crap, which fork do I use?
哦，糟了，我该用哪把叉子？
Damn it! She's gonna think I'm a moron.
该死！她会觉得我是个白痴。
What the hell are all these forks for?
这些叉子到底都是干嘛用的？
Which one did she use?
她用了哪一把？
Okay, chill. Be cool.
好了，放松点。要酷。
Just take a fork.
随便拿一把叉子。
Eat your salad.
吃你的沙拉。
Um...
嗯...
Mm?
嗯？
Oh, sorry. What were you saying?
哦，抱歉。你刚才说什么？
You're eating my salad.
你在吃我的沙拉。
Oh, yes. It's delicious.
哦，是的。很好吃。
So these slang words, they're actually very common, right?
所以这些俚语词，其实很常见，对吧？
Yeah, I think like you said, it's not likely that you'll find them in a dictionary.
是的，就像你说的，它们不太可能出现在字典里。
Of course. And you can find them in movies, or sometimes when you're having a conversation,
当然。你可以在电影里找到它们，或者有时候在对话中，
a very informal conversation with a native speaker,
和母语者进行非常非正式的对话时，
these words will slip out and these slang terms will come up.
这些词就会冒出来，这些俚语就会用到。
Exactly. And you know what? There's a great resource out there for wonderful English slang terms,
没错。你知道吗？有一个很好的资源可以找到精彩的英语俚语，
called UrbanDictionary.com.
叫 UrbanDictionary.com。
Exactly. If you ever see a word that maybe you can't find in the conventional dictionary,
没错。如果你看到一个可能在传统字典里找不到的词，
you're probably gonna find it there.
你很可能在那里找到它。
Yeah, we'll put a link up to it on the site.
是的，我们会在网站上放一个链接。
Alright. So also, if you have any questions or comments, be sure to come to our website, EnglishPod.com.
好的。另外，如果你有任何问题或评论，一定要来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Marco and I are there to answer all your questions,
我和 Marco 会在那里回答你所有的问题，
and we also got lots of resources, like links to Urban Dictionary.
而且我们还有很多资源，比如 Urban Dictionary 的链接。
Right. And also, if you have any questions on any other slang terms that you may have heard,
没错。还有，如果你对听到的其他俚语有任何疑问，
or how to use them, be sure to post it on the comment section.
或者不知道怎么用，一定要在评论区留言。
Well guys, thanks for listening to this lesson, and until next time, goodbye!
好了，各位，感谢收听这节课，下次再见，拜拜！